Guide to the William C. Bullitt Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Diplomatic and Public Service Papers, 1813-1956; Series II
  - Ambassador to the USSR
    - Hanson, George C., 1934 (Box 111, Folder 419)
    - Invitation lists, [1934] (Box 111, Folder 420)
    - Invitations, 1933-1935 (Box 111, Folder 421 - 425)
    - Memos, 1933-1935, undated (Box 112, Folder 426 - 427)
    - North China, undated (Box 112, Folder 428)
    - Personnel, Foreign Service, 1934-1936 (Box 112, Folder 429 - 430)
      See also: Oversize Folder 76
    - Railroad ticket purchases, 1935 (Box 112, Folder 431)
    - Spaso House, commissary bills, 1934-1935 (Box 112, Folder 432)
    - Spaso House, Jorgsin [?] bills, 1935 (Box 112, Folder 433 - 434)
    - Spaso House, misc. [includes photographs], 1933-1934 (Box 112, Folder 435 - 438)
    - State Department communications, 1933-1934 (Box 112, Folder 439)
    - Supplies, 1934 (Box 112, Folder 440)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1936 (Box 112, Folder 441 - 442)
  - Ambassador to France
    - Algerian trip, 1939-1940 (Box 113, Folder 443)
    - Applications for positions, 1938 (Box 113, Folder 444)
    - Chateau de St. Firmin, 1937-1939 (Box 113, Folder 445 - 449)
      See also: Oversize Folder 86
    - Christmas dossier, 1939 (Box 113, Folder 450)
    - Christmas telegrams, 1939 (Box 113, Folder 451)
    - Embassy inventories, 1938 (Box 113, Folder 452)
    - French Institute, 1937 (Box 113, Folder 453)
    - Household matters, 1936-1940 (Box 113, Folder 454 - 459)
    - Italy and the United States, 1939 (Box 113, Folder 460)
    - Joan of Arc altar dedication, 1940 (Box 113, Folder 461)
    - Memorabilia, 1937-1939 (Box 113, Folder 462)
      See also: Oversize Folder 16 - 21
    - Memos, 1936-1940, undated (Box 114, Folder 463 - 466)
    - Military file, 1939 (Box 114, Folder 467)
    - Nancy trip
      - Clippings, 1938 (Box 114, Folder 468 - 469)
      - Correspondence, general, 1938 (Box 114, Folder 470 - 472)
      - Speeches of Ambassador, 1938 (Box 114, Folder 473 - 475)
      - Speeches in reply to Ambassador, 1938 (Box 114, Folder 476)
      - Miscellaneous, 1937-1938 (Box 114, Folder 477 - 478)
        See also: Oversize Folder 52
    - Nimes visit, 1937-1939 (Box 115, Folder 479 - 481)
    - Offers of service, 1938-1940 (Box 115, Folder 482 - 487)
    - Offie, Carmel correspondence [includes photographs], 1938-1939 (Box 115, Folder 488 - 491)
    - Offie, Carmel correspondence [includes photographs], 1939-1940 (Box 116, Folder 492 - 498)
    - Personnel, 1938-1940 (Box 116, Folder 499 - 503)
    - Personnel, foreign service, 1937 (Box 116, Folder 504)
    - Publications received, 1937 (Box 116, Folder 505)
    - Publications received, 1938-1940 (Box 117, Folder 506 - 514)
    - Radio transcripts, 1939 (Box 117, Folder 515)
    - Requests for autographs, photographs, and stamps, 1940 (Box 117, Folder 516)
    - Situation de L'Armée de L'Air, 1940 (Box 117, Folder 517)
    - Social lists and events, 1937-1939 (Box 117, Folder 518 - 523)
    - Soviet Union, 1937-1939, undated (Box 118, Folder 524 - 525)
    - State Department telegrams, personal, 1940-1941 (Box 118, Folder 526)
    - Thanks for orchids from staff and others, 1939-1940 (Box 118, Folder 527)
    - Thanks for whiskey, etc., from personnel, 1939-1940 (Box 118, Folder 528)
    - Ukraine, 1939 (Box 118, Folder 529)
    - Wines and liquors, 1936-1938, undated (Box 118, Folder 530 - 532)
    - Miscellaneous, 1936-1940 (Box 118, Folder 533 - 535)
  - Special Assistant to the Secretary of the Navy
    - Cases for Capt. Beatty, 1942 (Box 121, Folder 587)
    - Civil affairs program, 1943 (Box 121, Folder 588)
    - General political, 1943 (Box 121, Folder 589)
    - "La Crise de L'Armistice", 1940-1942 (Box 121, Folder 590)
    - London war conference diary, 1942 (Box 121, Folder 591)
    - Memos, general, 1942-1943 (Box 121, Folder 592 - 594)
    - Memos to the President and Sec. Knox, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 595)
    - Memos to Sec. Frank Knox, 1942 (Box 122, Folder 596)
    - North African program, 1942-1943 (Box 122, Folder 597)
    - Capt. Pence, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 598)
    - Petroleum, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 599)
    - Policy papers for the President, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 600 - 601)
    - Political, general, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 602)
    - Publications received, 1942-1943 (Box 122, Folder 603 - 604)
    - Power program, 1942 (Box 122, Folder 605)
    - Rubber program, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 606)
    - Snead, Sam, 1942 (Box 122, Folder 607)
    - Soviet Union, 1942-1943 (Box 122, Folder 608 - 609)
    - Miscellaneous, 1942-1943 (Box 122, Folder 610 - 612)
  - Philadelphia mayoral campaign
    - Clippings, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 613)
    - Correspondence, A-B, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 614 - 616)
    - Correspondence, C-R, 1943 (Box 123, Folder 617 - 646)
    - Correspondence, S-Z, unidentified, 1943 (Box 124, Folder 647 - 660)
    - Personal, 1943 (Box 124, Folder 661 - 672)
    - Reports, 1937-1943 (Box 124, Folder 673 - 676)
    - Speeches
      - General, 1943 (Box 124, Folder 677 - 681)
      - General, 1943 (Box 125, Folder 682 - 707)
      - Acceptance speech, 1943 September 17 (Box 125, Folder 708 - 711)
      - Excerpts from Bullitt speeches, 1943 (Box 125, Folder 712 - 716)
      - Intolerance speech, 1943 (Box 126, Folder 717)
      - "Poland will live again," Academy of Music, 1943 (Box 126, Folder 718 - 721)
      - Second speech, 1943 September 30 (Box 126, Folder 722 - 724)
      - Speech material, 1943 (Box 126, Folder 725 - 734)
      - Statement announcing candidacy, 1943 (Box 126, Folder 735)
    - Subject files
      - Abercouph, Jules C., 1943 (Box 126, Folder 736)
      - Antisemitic-Communist propaganda, 1943 (Box 126, Folder 737)
      - Bulletin - Inquirer - editorials, 1943 (Box 126, Folder 738 - 747)
      - Campaign instructions, 1943 (Box 126, Folder 748)
      - Campaign literature, 1943 (Box 127, Folder 749 - 758)
      - Campaign suggestions, 1943 (Box 127, Folder 759 - 762)
      - City charter, 1943 (Box 127, Folder 763)
      - City council consolidation, 1943 (Box 127, Folder 764)
      - City Finances: 1942, 1943 (Box 127, Folder 765 - 767)
      - City finances and budget, 1943 (Box 127, Folder 768 - 776)
      - Civil service, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 777)
      - Corruption, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 778)
      - Councilmanic meetings, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 779 - 782)
      - Daily Worker attacks, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 783 - 794)
      - Education and recreation, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 795 - 797)
      - Frankfurter Zeitung photostats, etc., 1943 (Box 128, Folder 798)
      - Friends meeting, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 799)
      - Harris, David W., Chairman of Republican Central Committee, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 800)
      - Independent Republicans, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 801)
      - Labor, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 802)
      - Manual of Council, 1942 (Box 128, Folder 803)
      - Northeast Chamber of Commerce, 1943 (Box 128, Folder 804 - 806)
      - Post-war planning, 1941-1943 (Box 129, Folder 807 - 810)
      - Post-war reconstruction, 1942-1943 (Box 129, Folder 811 - 813)
        See also: Oversize Folder 98
      - Public relations, 1938-1943 (Box 129, Folder 814 - 820)
      - Public relations, 1938-1943 (Box 130, Folder 821 - 829)
      - Samuel speeches, 1943 (Box 130, Folder 830)
      - Transit, 1943 (Box 130, Folder 831 - 833)
      - Vote Jewish photostats, 1943 (Box 130, Folder 834)
      - Wage tax, 1941-1943 (Box 130, Folder 835)
      - Wage tax suit, 1943 (Box 130, Folder 836)
      - Water, 1943 (Box 130, Folder 837)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 130, Folder 838 - 845)
  - Free French Armed Forces [includes photographs and correspondence], 1944-1945 (Box 131, Folder 846 - 851)
    See also: Oversize Folder 90
  - Joint Congressional Committee on Foreign Economic Cooperation (China)
    - American aid, 1948, 1950 (Box 131, Folder 852 - 855)
    - China data, 1947-1948 (Box 131, Folder 856 - 861)
      See also: Oversize Folder 32
    - China data, 1947-1948 (Box 132, Folder 862 - 865)
    - Chinese air force, 1948 (Box 132, Folder 866 - 870)
    - Chinese communists, scrapbook on, 1947 (Box 132, Folder 871 - 873)
      See also: Oversize Folder 88
    - Communists, 1948 (Box 132, Folder 874)
    - Congressional report, 1948-1949 (Box 132, Folder 875 - 878)
      See also: Oversize Folder 91
    - Congressional report, 1948-1949 (Box 133, Folder 879 - 882)
    - Cotton, 1948 (Box 133, Folder 883)
    - Economic, 1948 (Box 133, Folder 884 - 885)
      See also: Oversize Folder 41
      See also: Oversize Folder 92
    - Economic Cooperation Administration, 1948 (Box 133, Folder 886 - 889)
    - Fertilizer, 1948 (Box 133, Folder 890)
    - Financial, 1948 (Box 133, Folder 891)
      See also: Oversize Folder 4
    - Hong Kong, 1948 (Box 133, Folder 892 - 893)
      See also: Oversize Folder 5
    - Inauguration of Chiang Kai-shek, 1948 (Box 133, Folder 894)
    - Laws and testimony, 1948 (Box 133, Folder 895 - 896)
    - Military, 1948 (Box 134, Folder 897 - 898)
      See also: Oversize Folder 78
    - Notes on conversations on China and Japan, 1948 (Box 134, Folder 899 - 900)
    - Petroleum, 1948 (Box 134, Folder 901)
    - Petroleum article data, 1948 (Box 134, Folder 902)
    - Programs, 1948 (Box 134, Folder 903)
    - State Department, [1948] (Box 134, Folder 904)
    - Miscellaneous [includes photographs], 1948 (Box 134, Folder 905 - 913)
      See also: Oversize Folder 93
    - Miscellaneous [includes photographs], 1948 (Box 135, Folder 914 - 917)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Bullitt reports on Soviet Union, 1936-1946 (Box 135, Folder 918 - 919)
    - Correspondence re Bullitt's desire to enter military service, 1944 (Box 135, Folder 920)
    - Eisenhower and Indochina, memos, 1954 (Box 135, Folder 921)
    - Foreign Service officer list, 1950 (Box 135, Folder 922)
    - Korea, memos, 1953 (Box 135, Folder 923)
    - Legion of Merit [includes photographs], 1947 (Box 135, Folder 924)
      See also: Oversize Folder 48
    - Memorandum of a conversation with Slessor and Hoyt Vandenberg, 1950 (Box 135, Folder 925)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 135, Folder 926)
    - Protocol, undated (Box 135, Folder 927)
    - State Department press releases on Soviet Union, 1933-1941 (Box 135, Folder 928)
- Writings, 1888-1984; Series III
  This series is comprised of original writings by Bullitt and others. It is organized into nine sections: Books, Journalism, Notes, Plays, Screenplay, Short stories, Speeches, Writings by others, and Unidentified manuscripts.
  The Books section contains drafts, clippings, and correspondence related to Bullitt's three published works: his critique of American policy toward the Soviet Union, The Great Globe Itself (1946), his novel, It's Not Done (1926), and his psychological study of Woodrow Wilson co-authored with Sigmund Freud, Thomas Woodrow Wilson (1966). The materials concerning Thomas Woodrow Wilson include manuscripts in Freud's hand, correspondence with Freud, various drafts, correspondence with publishers, and research materials. Some of the correspondence with publishers post-dates Bullitt's death and was apparently handled by his daughter Anne. The research materials include a 300-page manuscript biography of Woodrow Wilson written by Bullitt, most of which is unpublished. Only a small portion concerning Wilson's youth was published as a digest in the book. The manuscript biography apparently served as the empirical basis for Freud's and Bullitt's psychological analysis of Wilson. There are also drafts of Bullitt's unpublished novel "The Divine Wisdom," an incomplete memoir manuscript written in 1950 entitled "The Shining Adventure," and materials concerning other uncompleted book projects.
  The materials concerning Bullitt's career as a journalist, both before and after his work as a diplomat, are divided into two sub-sections: Articles and Research materials. The Articles files are organized by title and include mostly drafts but some contain related notes and copies of the final published version. The folders titled "Ford peace expedition" include a short diary kept by Bullitt, photographs, several copies of a satirical newsletter The Argosy produced by reporters on the trip, and other related printed matter, as well as notes and drafts from the articles Bullitt wrote about Ford's voyage. The Research materials contain printed matter, reports, notes, memoranda, and correspondence that appear to relate to topics Bullitt wrote about as a journalist in the late 1940s and early 1950s, most having to do with the threat of communism in East Asia and France. The large number of folders titled "Reference" contain printed matter, organized in rough chronological order, which appear to concern primarily the subjects of Bullitt's journalism.
  The Speeches section includes copies and drafts of Bullitt's published and unpublished speeches arranged chronologically and correspondence from the public in response to a 1940 speech he gave in Philadelphia which advocated American intervention in World War II. Many of the speech folders contain notes, clippings, and other materials that primarily relate to Bullitt's speeches, but also to his other journalistic or literary writings. The Plays, Poems, Screenplay, and Short Stories files document Bullitt's literary efforts beyond his novel writing and apparently none of this material has ever been published. The Notes section contains material related to Bullitt's work as a diplomat and journalist, his literary efforts, and his personal life. The notes have not been arranged by date or subject. Writings by others is made up of drafts and manuscripts by authors other than Bullitt including Paul Reynaud and William Langer. The Unidentified manuscripts are writings that cannot be readily identified as the work of Bullitt or another author. They are arranged by date although a majority of them are undated.
  - Books
    - "The Divine Wisdom"
      - Drafts, complete, undated (Box 136, Folder 1 - 18)
      - Draft fragments, undated (Box 136, Folder 19 - 23)
      - Draft fragments, undated (Box 137, Folder 24 - 25)
    - The Great Globe Itself
      - Belgian edition [correspondence], 1946 (Box 137, Folder 26)
      - Book reviews and miscellaneous, 1946-1947 (Box 137, Folder 27 - 29)
        See also: Oversize Folder 40
      - Charles Scribner's Sons correspondence, 1946 (Box 137, Folder 30)
      - Clippings, 1946 (Box 137, Folder 31 - 37)
      - Clippings, 1946 (Box 138, Folder 38 - 53)
      - Clippings, 1946 (Box 139, Folder 54 - 59)
      - Columbian edition [correspondence], 1947 (Box 139, Folder 60)
      - Congressional acknowledgments, 1947 (Box 139, Folder 61)
      - Contracts, 1946-1947 (Box 139, Folder 62)
      - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 139, Folder 63)
      - Danish edition [correspondence], 1946-1947 (Box 139, Folder 64)
      - Draft, chapter one, undated (Box 139, Folder 65)
      - Dutch edition [correspondence], 1946-1949 (Box 139, Folder 66)
      - English edition [correspondence], 1946-1949 (Box 139, Folder 67)
      - French edition [correspondence], 1946-1949 (Box 139, Folder 68)
      - German edition [correspondence], 1947-1948 (Box 139, Folder 69)
      - Italian edition [correspondence], 1946-1948 (Box 139, Folder 70)
      - Norwegian edition [correspondence], 1946-1948 (Box 139, Folder 71)
      - Portuguese edition [correspondence], 1946-1949 (Box 139, Folder 72)
      - Spanish edition [correspondence], 1946-1949 (Box 139, Folder 73)
      - Swedish edition [correspondence], 1946-1949 (Box 139, Folder 74)
      - Swiss edition [correspondence], 1946-1947 (Box 139, Folder 75)
    - It's Not Done
      - Clippings, 1926-1927 (Box 140, Folder 76 - 79)
      - Draft, 1926 (Box 140, Folder 80 - 88)
      - Draft fragments, undated (Box 140, Folder 89 - 96)
      - Draft fragments, undated (Box 141, Folder 97 - 100)
    - "The Shining Adventure" [memoirs], 1950 (Box 141, Folder 101 - 109)
    - Thomas Woodrow Wilson
      - Correspondence
        - Publishing [includes contracts and galleys], 1932, 1953-1984 (Box 141, Folder 110 - 114)
          See also: Oversize Folder 83 - 84
        - Publishing [includes contracts and galleys], 1932, 1953-1984 (Box 142, Folder 115 - 126)
          See also: Oversize Folder 74
        - Research, 1930-1932 (Box 142, Folder 127)
      - Drafts
        - Complete [or nearly so]
          - Carbon copy, undated (Box 142, Folder 128 - 133)
          - Cover die copy, undated (Box 143, Folder 134 - 139)
          - First draft, undated (Box 143, Folder 140 - 143)
          - Houghton Mifflin copy [copy edited], undated (Box 143, Folder 144 - 149)
          - Version with Anna Freud's revisions, 1966 (Box 144, Folder 150 - 155)
          - Version with typescript of revisions, undated (Box 144, Folder 156 - 162)
          - Versions, unidentified [a few annotations], undated (Box 144, Folder 163 - 165)
          - Versions, unidentified [a few annotations], undated (Box 145, Folder 166 - 182)
          - Versions, unidentified [a few annotations], undated (Box 146, Folder 183 - 190)
        - Partial
          - Chapter I [Freud manuscript], undated (Box 146, Folder 191)
          - Chapters I and II [annotated by Freud and Bullitt], undated (Box 146, Folder 192 - 195)
          - Chapters III-VII, incomplete [annotated by Freud and Bullitt], undated (Box 146, Folder 196)
          - Chapter IV fragments [annotated by Freud], undated (Box 146, Folder 197)
          - Digest, undated (Box 146, Folder 198 - 200)
          - Foreword by Bullitt, 1962, undated (Box 146, Folder 201 - 202)
          - Fragments, undated (Box 147, Folder 203 - 221)
          - Freud manuscript fragments [includes correspondence], 1927-1931 (Box 147, Folder 222 - 224)
          - Frontis photograph, undated (Box 147, Folder 225)
          - Introduction by Freud, undated (Box 147, Folder 226 - 227)
          - Outline, undated (Box 147, Folder 228)
      - Research materials
        - Edward M. House diary extracts, undated (Box 148, Folder 229)
        - Letters about Woodrow Wilson, copies, 1888-1890, 1915-1919 (Box 148, Folder 230)
        - Notes, 1930-1931 (Box 148, Folder 231)
        - Notes of conversations about Woodrow Wilson, 1930-1931 (Box 148, Folder 232 - 233)
        - "Notes on Woodrow Wilson"
          - [birth to 1903], undated (Box 148, Folder 234)
          - [childhood to Apr. 1917], undated (Box 148, Folder 235 - 237)
          - [Apr. 1917 to death], undated (Box 148, Folder 238 - 247)
          - Draft, annotated, undated (Box 149, Folder 248 - 256)
          - Draft fragments, undated (Box 149, Folder 257 - 261)
        - Printed matter, 1930-1931, undated (Box 149, Folder 262)
    - "Winning Wars and Losing the Peace", undated (Box 149, Folder 263 - 267)
      See also: Oversize Folder 23
    - Miscellaneous material for unidentified book project, 1935-1950 (Box 149, Folder 268 - 269)
  - Diary fragment, 1915 (Box 149, Folder 270)
  - Journalism
    - Articles
      - "Action, at last!", undated (Box 150, Folder 271 - 275)
      - "America to Europe", 1948 (Box 150, Folder 276)
      - "Bacchus and booze", undated (Box 150, Folder 277)
      - "The battle for France", undated (Box 150, Folder 278)
      - "British riots and French restraint", undated (Box 150, Folder 279)
      - "Can Truman avoid World War III", 1947 (Box 150, Folder 280)
      - "The Cold War is real war", 1950 (Box 150, Folder 281)
      - "Conservatives and convicts", undated (Box 150, Folder 282)
      - "Democratic policy in world affairs", undated (Box 150, Folder 283 - 284)
      - Ford peace expedition [includes diary, photographs, and printed matter], 1915-1916 (Box 150, Folder 285 - 291)
      - "Hell, Sunday, and superlatives", undated (Box 150, Folder 292)
      - "Hong Kong", undated (Box 150, Folder 293)
      - "Interview with Baron Von Stumm", 1915 (Box 150, Folder 294)
      - "The Kaiser and his God", 1916 (Box 150, Folder 295)
      - "The most unforgettable general I have known", undated (Box 151, Folder 296)
      - "The old ills of modern India", 1951 (Box 151, Folder 297)
      - "Report to the American people on China", 1947 (Box 151, Folder 298 - 301)
      - "The saddest war" [includes photographs], 1947-1948 (Box 151, Folder 302 - 305)
      - "Stalin's strategy for world conquest", undated (Box 151, Folder 306)
      - "Strategy of defeat", undated (Box 151, Folder 307)
      - "The strength of our new foreign policy", 1947 (Box 151, Folder 308)
      - "The sword without", [ca 1948] (Box 151, Folder 309 - 317)
      - "The sword without", [ca 1948] (Box 152, Folder 318 - 323)
      - "To govern is to foresee", undated (Box 152, Folder 324 - 327)
      - "The Treaty of Versailles", [1944] (Box 152, Folder 328)
      - "War corresponding de luxe", 1916 (Box 152, Folder 329)
      - "We can win in Korea", 1953 (Box 152, Folder 330)
      - Miscellaneous, 1916-1917, 1953, undated (Box 152, Folder 331)
    - Research materials
      - China [includes photographs], 1945-1950 (Box 152, Folder 332 - 336)
        See also: Oversize Folder 42 - 43
        See also: Oversize Folder 79
        See also: Oversize Folder 87
        See also: Oversize Folder 94
      - China [includes photographs], 1945-1950 (Box 153, Folder 337 - 350)
      - China trip, 1947-1948 (Box 154, Folder 351 - 353)
        See also: Oversize Folder 33
      - Chinese army nutrition program, 1954-1956 (Box 154, Folder 354 - 367)
        See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1882-1967 Folder 549
        See also: Oversize Folder 6
      - Chinese army nutrition program, 1954-1956 (Box 155, Folder 368 - 369)
      - Far East trip [includes photographs], 1951-1953 (Box 155, Folder 370 - 378)
      - Formosa [Taiwan], 1953-1954, undated (Box 155, Folder 379 - 384)
        See also: Oversize Folder 44
      - France, 1947, 1951, undated (Box 156, Folder 385 - 391)
      - France-China trip, 1947 (Box 156, Folder 392)
      - Hungary, 1947 (Box 156, Folder 393)
      - India and Southeast Asia [includes photographs], 1951 (Box 156, Folder 394 - 399)
        See also: Oversize Folder 45
      - Indochina, 1944-1948 (Box 157, Folder 400 - 410)
        See also: Oversize Folder 46
      - Indochina trip, 1947 (Box 157, Folder 411)
      - Japan, 1951-1953 (Box 157, Folder 412)
      - Korea, 1953-1954 (Box 157, Folder 413 - 416)
      - Reference, 1940-1948 (Box 158, Folder 417 - 429)
        See also: Oversize Folder 70
        See also: Oversize Folder 99
      - Reference, 1946-1952 (Box 159, Folder 430 - 442)
      - Reference, 1940-1957, undated (Box 160, Folder 443 - 452)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1947 (Box 160, Folder 453)
      - Sinkiang, 1947 (Box 160, Folder 454)
      - Soviet-German Nonaggression Pact, 1940-1946, undated (Box 160, Folder 455)
  - Notes [includes draft fragments] (Box 160, Folder 456 - 463)
  - Notes [includes draft fragments] (Box 161, Folder 464 - 485)
  - Plays
    - "Gobi", undated (Box 162, Folder 486 - 499)
    - "If you were young" with Ernesta Drinker Bullitt and Harrison Rhodes, undated (Box 162, Folder 500)
    - "The masterpiece", undated (Box 162, Folder 501)
    - "Our dear grandparents", undated (Box 162, Folder 502)
    - "Toys", undated (Box 163, Folder 503 - 505)
    - "The Tragedy of Woodrow Wilson", undated (Box 163, Folder 506 - 509)
    - Untitled fragment with notes, undated (Box 163, Folder 510)
    - "The wickedest man in the world", undated (Box 163, Folder 511 - 512)
  - Poems, 1901, [ca 1945], undated (Box 163, Folder 513)
  - Screenplay, "The peace makers of Paris", undated (Box 163, Folder 514)
  - Short stories
    - "The boy who would not play", 1920 (Box 163, Folder 515)
    - "Ever victorious", undated (Box 163, Folder 516)
    - "Hanunian[?]", undated (Box 163, Folder 517)
    - "The hero", undated (Box 163, Folder 518)